## BLURB

Software Engineer with collectively 1 year of experience in various industries including civic research/design, transportation, and defense; quick learner, passionate about quality code and user/developer experience, currently interested in contributing to software with a positive world impact within healthcare.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### CHESAPEAKE TECHNOLOGY INTERNATIONAL (CTI)

Associate Software Engineer — March 2020 - current

- Tech Stack: Java, JBoss Weld CDI, Gradle in Groovy, JFormDesigner
- Developing custom software for a contract customer within the defense industry
- Contributing to Government-owned Open Source (GOS) software being used widely across many departments within the US military
- Participated in company-wide week-long hackathon, worked with team to develop tool for detecting and analyzing various radio data, utilized AWS EC2/ECS, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Docker, Terraform
- Working in a distributed team with members from across the nation, with over 10 offices throughout the entire US from San Diego, CA to California, MD and now in Kailua, Hl.

#### **PROTOLAB**

Full Stack Developer — October 2019 - March 2020

- Tech Stack: React Hooks, TypeScript, Webpack, Firebase, Docker, CircleCl, Ant Design, Redux
- Developed new portal for Design for San Diego (D4SD), an innovation challenge structured around the human-centered design process that seeks to solve complex civic problems
- Worked with team of undergrad researchers/developers to develop dashboard platform where participants can submit solutions and professionals from industry can provide feedback
- Worked closely with project lead (associate professor), PhD students, and fellow grad and undergrad researchers in weekly scrum meetings, cross-team collaborations, and planning sessions

### **LYFT**

Front End Software Engineer Intern — June 2019 - September 2019

- Tech Stack: React Hooks, Typescript, MobX, Deck.gl
- Developed an internal front end visualization platform / single-page application (SPA), providing a common SDK for map visualization that is used by multiple developers at Lyft
- Worked in Saltstack and Docker to reconfigure webapp infrastructure amidst major monorepo to multirepo transition, performed full stack responsibilities
- Led major redesign project of UI/UX of webapp, organizing and planning implementation timeline for design components from contracted design firm, implemented core components
- Worked closely with experienced front end engineers, product designers, infrastructure engineers, etc. in meetings with clients, architectural discussions, and planning sessions

### UCSD CSE DEPARTMENT

CSE Head Tutor — April 2018 - March 2020

- Relavent Languages: Java, C, C++, ARM Assembly
- Tutored CSE 12: Basic Data Structures and OOD, CSE 30: Computer Organization and Systems Programming, CSE 110: Software Engineering, CSE 141: Introduction to Computer Architecture
- Responsibilities involved holding lab hours each week to assist students in programming assignments, grade and evaluate assignments and projects, attending and proctoring lectures and labs
- Head tutor responsibilities included developing and managing course websites, distributing work to other tutors, creating and uploading course worksheets

# Course Projects———

### **FLICK**

Software Engineering, Sophomore Year — 2018

- Utilized HTML and React to develop screens for community-driven item renting app.
- Worked as UI/UX Specialist in quarter-long project simulating Software Engineering internship.
- Used InVision Studio to design screens used by mobile and webapp front-end teams.
- Using UX heuristics, designed user experience for navigation through app screens and ease of use.



github.com/lliang19





Itliang.com



in in/Itliang

# **EDUCATION**

### **UNIVERSITY OF CALFORNIA, SAN DIEGO**

B.S., Computer Science Major / Interaction Design Minor Sep 2016 - Mar 2020 *Major GPA* − 3.419 Overall GPA - 3.314

- · Advanced Data Structures
- · Design / Analysis of Algorithms
- · Computer Networks and **Networked Services**
- · Principles of Computer Operating Systems
- · Programming Languages and Compilers
- · Web Mining and Recommender Systems
- · Wireless Embedded Systems
- Human Computer Interaction Programming Studio

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

 Java 00000 • Python . . . . . JS/Typescript React . . . . . C/C++ . . . . . .

### I've also dabbled in:

 AWS Dockerfile

HTML/CSS

• Express

DeckGL

NodeJS

Terraform

. . . . . .

MobX

Saltstack

Haskell